<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches | Sreenath Paleri</title>
    <link>/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Researches</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Researches</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurements and parameterizations of surface energy budget over complex terrain</title>
      <link>/research/noaa-splash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/noaa-splash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multi-scale heterogeneities  arising from terrain-induced and land surface variabilities  present in complex watersheds require accurate measurements and models of surface-atmospheric exchanges and watershed dynamics. The spatial and temporal variability of energy and water budgets over the complex terrain can influence hydrological and biogeochemical interactions that can strongly affect groundwater recharge and downstream water quality within the watershed as well as influence local and regional biosphere-atmosphere transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scaling and accurate model representations of these interactions across complex terrains based on single-point or local measurements present a non-trivial scientific challenge.
Observations were made of surface energy balance components at NOAA surface flux and mobile SURFRAD radiation stations separated by 5 kilometers along the East River, Colorado, Watershed as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psl.noaa.gov/splash/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SPLASH&lt;/a&gt; field campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working on the gap-filled diurnal and seasonal evolution of surface energy balance components as the study domain transitions from low to high snow cover to study the spatial variability of the measured fluxes along the valley axis, with focus on the possible influences of local advection and thermally driven circulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The measured fluxes are being compared with a new bulk Richardson number parameterization for heat fluxes over heterogeneous land surfaces, introduced in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/MWR-D-21-0047.1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lee et al. 2021&lt;/a&gt;, here extended for complex topography. Our findings provide credence for implementing such a parameterization for surface fluxes and turbulence statistics for model representations of surface-atmospheric exchanges in operational NWP and data products. I am hoping to present this work in the AGU 2023 Fall Meeting. If you are interested and would like to talk more please feel free to contact me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Eddy Simulations of surface heterogeneity induced secondary circulations</title>
      <link>/research/cheesehead-palm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/cheesehead-palm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have hinted at the key role of land surface heterogeneities for developing
secondary circulations in the atmospheric boundary layer. Observational studies and large
eddy simulation (LES) models have been used to understand the role of these circulations in
boundary-layer development, cloud processes, and documented biases in measurements such
as eddy-covariance energy fluxes. However, these studies have been limited in their ability to
capture these events and robustly test hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Luise-Wanner&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Luise Wanner&lt;/a&gt; at KIT and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Matthias-Suehring&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Matthias Suhring&lt;/a&gt; at IMUK Leibniz Universität Hannover to setup realistic simulations of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://flux.aos.wisc.edu/projects/2018/6/19/cheesehead19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CHEESEHEAD19&lt;/a&gt; field experiment days. The Parallelized LES Model &lt;a href=&#34;https://palm.muk.uni-hannover.de/trac&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PALM&lt;/a&gt; (Maronga et al. 2020) is being used for numerical simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accurately simulate the physical processes as observed during the the field experiment as realistic as possible, we apply a Land Surface Model (LSM) with coupled soil, radiation and a Plant Canopy Model (PCM) for the domain. The use of the LSM and PCM runs instead of prescribed surface fluxes will enable the investigation of surface atmospheric feed backs such as self-reinforcement of mesoscale circulations over the heterogeneous study domain ([Wanner et al. 2022])(&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-021-00649-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-021-00649-7&lt;/a&gt;). This offers a detailed analysis of the physical processes involved and comparisons with observations as well as, direct interaction to the synoptic and radiative forcing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inbuilt LSM implementation is based on the ECMWF-IFS land surface parametrization (H-TESSEL) and its adaptation in the DALES model (Heus et al. 2010). The canopy is modeled as a porous viscous medium that removes momentum from the flow (Shaw &amp;amp; Schumann, 1992; Watanabe, 2004), and acts as source/sink for heat, humidity, or passive scalar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We setup simulations for two days in the summer ( Aug. 22 and 23 2019) and two days in the fall(Sep. 24 and 25 2019), with land use classes, soil and vegetation data as measured/observed during the field experiment. Since the modeling domain is forested, the observed tree tops are being resolved using the inbuilt PCM in PALM. The forest canopy is initialized using observed parameters from canopy LiDAR measurements (Andresen et al. 2019) and field observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manuscript detailing the model setup and validation is currently under review in Geoscientific Model Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we ask whether diagnosing these circulations and quantifying the transport occurring at their corresponding scales can help us observe all the relevant scales of surface atmospheric transport. We use the LES model PALM to simulate diurnal cycles for the chosen four days chosen from late summer to early fall over a large (27x30 km) heterogeneous study domain that was the field site for CHEESEHEAD19. The simulations were initialized using NOAA - HRRR as large-scale forcing data over the study domain. Our preliminary analysis shows a good match between the simulated and radiosonde measured profiles. Sample comparison plots for summer runs below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;profiles-palm-iop02.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;profiles-palm-iop02&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signals of secondary circulations induced due to the surface heterogeneities were diagnosed using time and ensemble averaging following Maronga and Raasch (2013). Below you can see a short animation of 3D iso-surfaces of surface heterogeneity induced vertical wind during the free convective, August case study day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;w_hi_3d_iop02_day2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;w_hi_3d_iop02_day2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manuscript detailing the contributions from these circulations to total surface heat fluxes and an analysis of their length scales is currently under review in Boundary Layer Meteorology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space-scale resolved surface-atmospheric fluxes</title>
      <link>/research/cheesehead-uwka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/cheesehead-uwka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Earth’s surface is heterogeneous at multiple scales owing to spatial variability in various properties. The atmospheric responses to these heterogeneities through fluxes of energy, water, carbon and other scalars are scale-dependent and non-linear. Although these exchanges can be measured using the eddy covariance technique, widely used tower-based measurement approaches suffer from spectral losses in lower frequencies when using typical averaging times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, spatially resolved measurements such as airborne eddy covariance measurements can detect such larger scale &lt;code&gt;(meso-beta, meso-gamma)&lt;/code&gt; transport. To evaluate the prevalence and magnitude of these flux contributions  we applied wavelet analysis to airborne flux measurements over a heterogeneous mid-latitude forested landscape, interspersed with open water bodies and wetlands. The airborne measurements were made during the Chequamegon Heterogeneous Ecosystem Energy-balance Study Enabled by a High-density Extensive Array of Detectors (CHEESEHEAD19) intensive field campaign (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/BAMS-D-19-0346.1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Butterworth et al. 2021&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airborne experiment was designed with the help of numerical experiments (Large Eddy Simulations with virtual flight scenarios) to maximise spatial coverage over the domain, ensure adequate sampling of larger scale eddies and ensure crew safety.
I was responsible for setting up the simulations that provided virtual flight data for the scenario analysis.The Parallelized Atmospheric LES Model (PALM), forced by surface flux maps from Metzger et al. 2013 (reanalysis calculated from tall tower measurements using ERF) was used to simulate typical summer conditions around the field site. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-2021-86&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Metzger et al. 2021&lt;/a&gt; provides details about the numerical simulations, analysis framework and design strategy used to come up with the final flight patterns for the airborne measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;forcings2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Surface sensible heat flux with one design flight pattern&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experimental study design aimed to sample the landscape transition from late summer to early fall and the associated ABL responses. The CHEESEHEAD19 airborne dataset presents a unique opportunity to analyse long periods of airborne EC over long legs (30 km) in a heterogeneous region over multiple times a year with differing patterns of surface sensible and latent heat fluxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we ask, how do spatial scales of surface-atmosphere fluxes vary over heterogeneous surfaces across the day and across seasons?  To get a quantitative estimate, the measured fluxes were separated into smaller-scale turbulent and larger-scale mesoscale contributions. We found significant mesoscale contributions to sensible and latent heat fluxes through summer to autumn which wouldn’t be resolved in single point tower measurements through traditional time-domain half-hourly Reynolds decomposition.
&lt;img src=&#34;seasonal_fluxes.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;seasonal_fluxes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To investigate how the measured mesoscale contributions vary over the course of a research flight and spatially over the domain, the measured fluxes are back–projected to their surface source as gridded two-dimensional data following the flux topography method of Mauder, Desjardins, and MacPherson (2008). Flux topographies are the footprint-weighted flux contributions measured across the domain from the airborne data (Amiro, 1998).
&lt;img src=&#34;LE_flux_topo.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;LE_flux_topo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, including a scale resolved picture of fluxes and their seasonal transition, please have a look at our manuscript detailing the findings in JGR-Atmospheres &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2022JD037138&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial and temporal variability of surface heat fluxes across the Indian subcontinent.</title>
      <link>/research/incompass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/incompass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.met.rdg.ac.uk/~sws05agt/incompass_limitless/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;INCOMPASS&lt;/a&gt; was an intensive field experiment conducted in 2016 across the Indian subcontinent. The campaign was jointly funded by the Natural Environment Research Council (NERC) in the United Kingdom and Ministry of Earth Sciences (MoES) in India under the Drivers of Variability in the South Asian Monsoon programme. The experiment had an airborne and ground based observational campaigns, chiefly consisting of research flights on the Facility for Airborne Atmospheric Measurement (FAAM) Atmospheric Research Aircraft and an array of surface-flux towers (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.3633&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Turner, AG, Bhat, GS, Martin, GM, et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surface flux tower network was designed to collect high-frequency and high quality surface flux data that could inform the joint Indo-UK land-atmosphere interactions modeling efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working as a Project Scientist with &lt;a href=&#34;https://caos.iisc.ac.in/faculty/bhat.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prof. G. S. Bhat&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://caos.iisc.ac.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Centre for Atmospheric and Oceanic Science, Indian Institute of Science&lt;/a&gt; I was responsible for the installation and maintanence of the relevant instruments at four of the field sites (Jaisalmer, Ahmadabad, Patna, Bangalore) spanning different climatic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instruments and software handled :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CSAT-3 Sonic Anemometers and EC-150 Open path CO2, H20 gas analyzer from Campbell Scientifc to measure insitu surface fluxes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming the CR-1000 dataloggers using CRBasic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flux calculations were performed using Eddy Pro. as detailed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.3688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bhat, GS, Morrison, R, Taylor, CM, et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thies Clima laser precipitation monitors to measure precipitation intensity and droplet size spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kipp and Zonen net radiometers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
