<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Large Eddy Simulations | Sreenath Paleri</title>
    <link>/tags/large-eddy-simulations/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/large-eddy-simulations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Large Eddy Simulations</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Large Eddy Simulations</title>
      <link>/tags/large-eddy-simulations/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large Eddy Simulations of surface heterogeneity induced secondary circulations</title>
      <link>/research/cheesehead-palm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/cheesehead-palm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies have hinted at the key role of land surface heterogeneities for developing
secondary circulations in the atmospheric boundary layer. Observational studies and large
eddy simulation (LES) models have been used to understand the role of these circulations in
boundary-layer development, cloud processes, and documented biases in measurements such
as eddy-covariance energy fluxes. However, these studies have been limited in their ability to
capture these events and robustly test hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Luise-Wanner&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Luise Wanner&lt;/a&gt; at KIT and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Matthias-Suehring&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Matthias Suhring&lt;/a&gt; at IMUK Leibniz Universität Hannover to setup realistic simulations of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://flux.aos.wisc.edu/projects/2018/6/19/cheesehead19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CHEESEHEAD19&lt;/a&gt; field experiment days. The Parallelized LES Model &lt;a href=&#34;https://palm.muk.uni-hannover.de/trac&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PALM&lt;/a&gt; (Maronga et al. 2020) is being used for numerical simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accurately simulate the physical processes as observed during the the field experiment as realistic as possible, we apply a Land Surface Model (LSM) with coupled soil, radiation and a Plant Canopy Model (PCM) for the domain. The use of the LSM and PCM runs instead of prescribed surface fluxes will enable the investigation of surface atmospheric feed backs such as self-reinforcement of mesoscale circulations over the heterogeneous study domain ([Wanner et al. 2022])(&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-021-00649-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10546-021-00649-7&lt;/a&gt;). This offers a detailed analysis of the physical processes involved and comparisons with observations as well as, direct interaction to the synoptic and radiative forcing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inbuilt LSM implementation is based on the ECMWF-IFS land surface parametrization (H-TESSEL) and its adaptation in the DALES model (Heus et al. 2010). The canopy is modeled as a porous viscous medium that removes momentum from the flow (Shaw &amp;amp; Schumann, 1992; Watanabe, 2004), and acts as source/sink for heat, humidity, or passive scalar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We setup simulations for two days in the summer ( Aug. 22 and 23 2019) and two days in the fall(Sep. 24 and 25 2019), with land use classes, soil and vegetation data as measured/observed during the field experiment. Since the modeling domain is forested, the observed tree tops are being resolved using the inbuilt PCM in PALM. The forest canopy is initialized using observed parameters from canopy LiDAR measurements (Andresen et al. 2019) and field observations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we ask whether diagnosing these circulations and quantifying the transport occurring at their corresponding scales can help us observe all the relevant scales of surface atmospheric transport. We use the LES model PALM to simulate diurnal cycles for the chosen four days chosen from late summer to early fall over a large (27x30 km) heterogeneous study domain that was the field site for CHEESEHEAD19. The simulations were initialized using NOAA - HRRR as large-scale forcing data over the study domain. Our preliminary analysis shows a good match between the simulated and radiosonde measured profiles. Sample comparison plots for summer runs below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;profiles-palm-iop02.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;profiles-palm-iop02&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I am working on extracting signals of secondary circulations induced due to the surface heterogeneities using time and ensemble averaging following Maronga and Raasch (2013). The dynamical nature of the structures will be  compared between the summer and autumn
simulations, showing differing atmospheric boundary layer stabilities. The impact of these
secondary circulations on local turbulent fluxes and simulated surface energy balance will also
be investigated. I am hoping to present this work at AGU Fall meeting 2022 in Chicago. Let me know if you&amp;rsquo;d like to meet up and talk more !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;w-iop02-30min.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;w-iop02-30min&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
